Hello, I'm your host David Bernard and
with me today RevenueCat CEO Jacob
Eiting. Our guest today is Nathan
Hudson, a two-time former head of
growth, this year's app marketer of the
year, and founder of Perceptics, a
full-service growth agency for mobile
apps focused on driving profitable user
growth, retention, and revenue. On the
podcast, we talk with Nathan about the
strategic opportunity of web-to-app. How
and when to use web-to-app, and why one
app found success using webinars in
their web-to-app funnel.
Hey Nathan, thanks so much for joining
us on the podcast today. Hey David, it's
great to be here. Been meaning to have
you on for a long time, so it's great to
finally make it happen. We've talked
about this for almost a year. It's been
a while, long time coming. Yeah, just
excited. One of my favorite podcasts, in
fact, it is my favorite podcast.
Come on, that's just pandering.
I'll take it, though. And Jacob, nice to
to have you on the pod today. Thank you.
It's It's nice to see Nathan. And we met
in the YMCA weight room in San
Francisco, but it's good to see you
virtually and we didn't get a ton of
time to talk when we were at Raga in San
Francisco, so I'm excited to dig in a
little bit. Awesome. So, the topic today
is web-to-app. It's been a huge topic of
2024 and I think going to continue to be
one of the leading topics of 2025 for
reasons we'll get into. But I think the
first place to start out because I think
there is a lot of confusion around it is
what do we mean by web-to-app? How do
you think about web-to-app? And do you
have an opinion on the spelling? Is it w
e b the number two a p p or is it web t
o?
Asking the hard-hitting questions,
David.
Yeah, that's tough. It's It's funny you
say it because I was working on some
content a couple of months ago and I
wasn't sure whether to title it
web-to-app t o web-to-app two. So, I
looked at how you guys named it at Raga.
I looked at loads of different, you
know, posts and and articles and I think
that this web number two app is becoming
the staple way of referring to
web-to-app. Um I don't know if it's
because web-to-app is already taken. No,
it's just cool. It's like Boys II Men,
you know what I mean? It's just like
It's like a hip thing to do, I guess.
It is kind of funny that we're just like
making up words in this industry at this
point.
I think all words are made up at some
point, David, so it's like, you know.
But it has been a thing that like kind
of emerged organically. I I've been
aware of the concept for a long time,
right? We We even experimented with this
kind of stuff at Elevate 10 years ago.
But it's been in the last, I feel like
18 months when I finally heard so many
people have been emailing me being like,
"Do you Do you all have a web-to-app
solution? Like what are you all doing
for web-to-app?" And at first I was
like, "Well, yeah, you can use this and
whatever." But I've I've come to learn
it's actually kind of a It's a whole
thing, right? And so, yeah, what does it
mean, Nathan? Tell me finally so I know.
Well, good question. I like to think The
reason I like to define web-to-app
firstly is because I think there are a
lot of people who just assume web-to-app
means building one of those web
onboarding quizzes. Yeah, that's what I
assumed. Yeah. Most people I speak to,
whenever I say web-to-app, they think,
"Oh, so I need a quiz, I need onboarding
journey." So, I think just taking it a
few steps back helps. And yeah, simply
it's the process of converting traffic
on the web or starting to convert
traffic on the web before directing them
to your app. So, I like to think of it
as wherever we are in the funnel, at
some point in that journey, we are going
to leverage the web intentionally or
unintentionally to help us convert
users. So, like practical takeaways. You
You kind of mentioned a few there, like
So, a lot of people do do quizzes and
super popular. We talked to a lot of
them on the podcast, like they have a
quiz. But practically, like do you have
like buckets of like, you know, minimal
web-to-app all the way to like full
web-to-app? Is there Give me some
examples of like what you think of as
web-to-app? I mean, the quiz funnel is
the most common. I think it's It's
worth, you know, saying that it is the
most common. But things like blog posts,
you know, directing meta traffic or
TikTok traffic to a specific blog post
and then having people download the app
from there, sending people from YouTube
videos to long-form webinars or videos.
So, web-to-app. At the end of the
webinar, you might sell the app or
position, "Hey, we have a product. You
can buy it on our site." All the way
through to just basic landing page with
a buy now button. So, I think there are
loads of different ways to to slice and
dice it and we can get into some of the
rationale behind each of those and the
the use cases for those. But really, I
like to think that the basic setup is
just we have a landing page and a sales
page on the web and we're trying to sell
like a e-com brand would like a lot of
SaaS products do. And then we kind of
build around that based on what the
user's looking for.
So, at the highest highest level, it's
just having some function, some
touchpoint on the web before people get
to the app. And then you would even say
that that's not The definition wouldn't
necessarily even include that you're
sending ad traffic to it. Like we talked
to an app Nundo Run on the podcast.
Their main source of traffic was people
searching alternative to Couch to 5K.
And they had this one blog post that
ranked really high for that. People went
to the blog post, then people go from
the blog post to the App Store to
becoming a subscriber. So, you would
even like lump organic traffic in that.
It's just like creating a touchpoint on
the web as people get to the app.
Exactly that. And I would say it gets
not vague, but it gets more complex in
that I wouldn't even say that it has to
be cold traffic or that it has to be
people who haven't used your product.
Often times, you can reactivate churned
users via the web. Uh you know, whether
that's an email campaign to churn subs,
pushing them to the web to start a new
trial or new subscription, still
web-to-app. Maybe it's
app-to-web-to-app, but it's it's
web-to-app.
It's using the web as either some part
part of your acquisition funnel or
retention funnel, right? And like yeah,
I think I guess it's It's a good way to
frame it because, you know, I think in
my mind where we sit and how I've been
thinking about this technology It's from
a technology perspective. It's like the
purchasing and the the quizzes and like
all of the things that have kind of
become synonymous with this. But I mean,
really you're talking about just using
the web as this like more open platform
where you can own more of your
distribution, which is always the
problem with the App Stores. I mean, the
App Stores you have Apple Search Ads.
You can do click-to-install ads, I
guess. But like your ability to to
control the, you know, to have control
over your acquisition funnel is pretty
limited. I mean, the web just gives you
a ton of more tools that you can use. Um
like you were mentioning content, like
whatever, just like good sales pages.
And then not even Maybe it doesn't even
include a purchase, right? It's just
thinking about driving users to content
and then content into the app. Um
because people search stuff, right? On
the internet. It's like a thing. And
then of course, we can talk I guess
we'll talk too about like what the some
of those more like uh technical aspects
of it, like actually converting things
like that. So, all of that leads into
why, which we kind of touched on that a
little bit already, but like why should
apps be considering using the web more?
Again, we can do some some more nuanced,
some more buckets. I like to break it
down based on app size and app stage
because I think there is a clear
division between benefits for really
massive apps or apps that have been
around a long time doing multiple
millions in monthly revenue versus
smaller apps who are just looking to get
their first acquisition channel going
beyond, you know, organic ASO.
Now, for those smaller apps, I really
think there are three benefits. The main
one being cash flow. Right? Which is I
don't have to wait so long to receive my
money if I take the purchase on the web.
Now, I've spoken to loads of people,
differing views. Some people agree or
disagree. It's a question of is it the
fees? Is it the attribution? Having
worked with a lot of early-stage apps
who are just trying to get one paid
channel working,
they always have this issue of, "Well, I
mean, even if I spend 3K this month,
which is a really small amount and not
advisable, but even if I spend 3K this
month and make 50K, I'm not going to be
able to spend that next month
potentially, so I can't I can't do
anything. Like I'm I'm stuck." It
interrupts your iteration cycles, right?
So, I think that is, you know, by far
the biggest advantage of testing on the
web. When you're first launching a paid
channel, you can just build that
feedback loop. And it's kind of what you
want to do with the performance channel
anyway.
Yeah, and even then, then 3K can
actually become enough money to learn
something, right? Cuz you could even do
like a thousand dollars of acquisition,
learn stuff literally in a day, and then
do an iteration. And you will And then,
you know, if you're using Stripe or
whatever, I think they do almost
same-day payouts, right? So, you can get
that. I guess it's obvious in hindsight,
but like the combination of keeping 95%
of your your revenue net of fees, and
then on top of that getting it
instantaneously is a huge windfall like
if you're cash-strapped. Yeah, I've
talked a lot about the fees and how
small apps, you know, only pay 15%
anyway on both Google and Apple. But
that time value of money thing, like You
talk about like on the worst-case
scenario, like the App Store might be
like 60 days net of spend or yeah, or
could be like
65 is the Yeah. Yeah, you can imagine
you're easily easily renting that money
for that amount of time is 15%, right? A
short-term loan is going to cost you
probably nearly that. So, the fee almost
doesn't even matter at that point,
really. And the 15% break, it's
important, but like compounded together,
I I never really thought about that.
That's That is huge. For small apps,
though, how do you think about
conversion? I mean, this is something
I've always been concerned about is is
you know, for an app that has like no
brand, no Is there a reticence on the
part of consumers to to pay on the web
for some random app they just heard
about through a Google ad or whatever?
It depends. Typically, we we don't see,
you know, huge disparities on conversion
between web and app.
Often times, it's higher conversion on
the web. Um especially if we're talking
about, you know, low ticket subscription
products. And even more so for high
ticket actually, but just for a second
if we talk about these low ticket
products,
yeah, it's not an issue. I think it can
be the case that if you're directing
traffic just to a landing page, as we
spoke about before, and then trying to
get people to purchase without a trial,
without a quiz, without any context, and
your landing page really isn't that
great, then yeah, you're going to
struggle. But similarly, a lot of small
apps have hardly any reviews and a hard
paywall and are still able to convert
organic traffic. So, I think, you know,
applying the same approach on web makes
a lot of sense.
And I think we talk about control, there
are things you can do on web to kind of
make you seem more impressive than you
are. It's hard to stand out on the App
Store, right? Yeah, that's a really good
point. Like when you have like 10
reviews on the App Store and maybe you
had a bug in your 1.0 and so you're
actually only rated like 3.5 stars and
you only have 10 ratings. It's like you
can create an aura on the web that looks
a lot more impressive than your 3.5
stars on the App Store. Yeah, and a good
template for WordPress or whatever.
So, you mentioned there were several
reasons. So, we've gone through cash
flow and fees. What are the the next two
things that you think about on why
smaller apps should even consider a web
to app? Yeah, the next two are kind of
linked. The first one is attribution.
Now, it's becoming less of a reason to
switch to web to app. I'm specifically
talking about, you know, mobile
subscription apps that are pushing meta
as their first channel. Often times, at
least from the founders and teams I've
spoken to, beyond organic traffic, the
first channel people think to try
is an ASA maybe or meta. And when it
comes to meta, when scan was the only
way of attributing traffic, it was a
real big issue. Like if you weren't
spending 10K plus a month, you weren't
going to hit your privacy thresholds,
you weren't going to see your your
postbacks, it was going to be a problem.
Now with meta's AM, aggregated event
measurement, it's slightly different.
So, it has leveled the playing field.
But there is still a advantage of using
web in that you can pretty much spend,
as Jacob said, 1K and learn something.
And that can be fine. And you can do
that on web. I would not want to launch
any kind of app promotion campaign with
a 1K budget or a 2K budget just because
I'd be pretty cautious about what we're
going to get back in a given time frame.
So, I think the fact that it's slightly
easier to attribute on web, benefit
three, means benefit four, I can spend
less money as a smaller app to actually
make some progress. Yeah, actually, you
know, exactly where those people were
coming from. You know very well their
conversion. You can really tell
something about that. I mean, we this is
analogous though not the same, but back
in my my core mobile development days,
it's like we used to soft launch apps on
Android because we knew even just
background noise on Android we could get
500 downloads a day. And like it didn't
matter. We didn't need that many cuz we
would launch a super busted version of
the app. And then we would get like a
trickle of downloads and we would just
look at all we'd watch we'd literally
watch the session replays for like all
500 of those users. And we would learn a
ton and it like wasn't statistically
significant, wasn't scalable, but it
didn't matter cuz like all we needed was
to start that engine of information,
that that loop of like iteration. And
that's kind of what you're talking about
here. It's like you can spend small
amounts of money, learn a little bit,
and then you don't need to actually
scale or actually make money. I mean,
it's nice if you don't lose all of that
money, but really the value there is
like the information because you'll make
money when you scale it, right? Like
that's that's the whole the whole
mission. So. On that front, how has
Apple's changes to Safari impacted
attribution for web to app? Cuz I know
like they're deprecating I mean, like
cookies, all the privacy stuff that
Apple has done in Safari. Has that had
an impact in that same time frame that
Apple introduced app tracking
transparency? A small impact, nowhere
near as big an impact as ATT. Cuz you
can still use UTM parameters, right? And
Apple's not blocking those. I think it
would be interesting to see, you know,
always hear will Google run into
something next or, you know, we don't
know what's going to happen with all the
rest of the browsers, but I think as
long as we have UTM tracking, we can see
what we need to see. We can go to
Mixpanel Amplitude, we can see our
users, we can, as Jacob said, dive in
and watch those funnels. So, I don't
think it's been such a big issue yet,
but it's definitely something that
people have spoken about or kind of wary
of.
Um, but very few actually, David. I
think you're probably only one of three
people ever mentioned it, so.
Yeah, it's always Apple's like kind of
sometimes missing the mark, but like I
mean, like UTMs are fairly inert, right?
Because you encode them usually in the
link you're putting into a campaign or
whatever. So, they're never all that
targeted. They can't really convey
personal information in them. You just
kind of get a bucket of people. And
yeah, it's like when I analyze it
attribution inbound data for RevenueCat,
you know, we got ads and all kinds of
other sources. It's just like
so much nicer like to know like kind of
where users came from. And like I don't
feel bad about it. It's not super creepy
or anything like this. It's just like,
oh, did they click on us in a search
term? It's like, okay, that's nice to
know, right? Like And so, I've always
said this I've probably said it 20 times
on this podcast, but like this is with
the App Store conversion process
specifically, but I feel like by Apple
like not allowing UTMs to flow through
the App Store download, they've actually
made privacy way worse because basically
all these like Adjusts of the world. I
mean, not to don't want to talk ill of
our trusted partners or anything like
this, but like basically the entire
fingerprinting industry was created
to circumvent the lack of UTM parameters
on the App Stores. And if they just
allowed a little bit of privacy like
with that UTM stuff. But I think it is
worth it's worth highlighting that's
kind of the core one of the core
advantages here is things attribution
not only is it like it's you don't even
need a partner for it. Like you don't
need a MMP, you don't need anything. You
just encode UTM params, make sure that's
making it into your funnel somewhere or
into your data side somewhere. It's
really easy to break up your inbounds
and start to get qualitative. It's just
saying it's one of the numbers data on
what's performing. This is like a whole
'nother podcast, but I I would be
interested for your take if you're
willing to share. Facebook's AEM is
essentially fingerprinting and yet Apple
lets it happen, which is the whole state
of the industry is just bizarre to me
because Apple made this big deal with
app tracking transparency, they like
fingerprinting is against the rules, but
Facebook, Adjust, AppsFlyer, individual
app developers, other ad networks, like
everybody just moved to fingerprinting.
Facebook's doing the best at it, but
it's technically a violation of Apple's
rules, but they're like turning the
other cheek. It's just bizarre to me.
Any thoughts? Yeah, I was speaking about
this someone a couple of weeks ago. I
love AEM, so
let's say it start with that.
I don't
I don't want it to go anywhere.
I don't think Facebook are doing
anything. No. This is news to me, by the
way. I'm so bad at all this ad tech
stuff. Like uh It's crazy because I
mean, there have been some big accounts
that we fully migrated from scan to AEM
because it's that much more accurate.
And it's like
maybe four, five months ago, we would
only really recommend it to smaller
apps, smaller clients. Eight, 10 months
ago it was really bad and shabby and
wasn't really good. Now it's really
strong. So, yeah, whatever they've got
going on, it works really well. And I
encourage anyone who's pushing app
promotion campaigns to try that on meta.
But yeah, I don't I don't understand why
Apple haven't jumped on it, but I'm not
complaining. But I don't know. I'd have
to look at the technology more deeply to
understand exactly what it's doing, but
you know, again, it's like I don't think
I mean, we're getting we're getting
probably off the off the beat here into
like industry news, but like or industry
prognostication, but like I do think
it's just
sort of the understanding there's way
too much economic value locked up if we
don't allow developers to make some sort
of understanding of the quality of the
customers that they're paying to
attract. You know what I mean? Like
everybody stands to benefit if we can
understand are the users I'm trying to
bring into my product actually users
interested in my product, right? There's
like just market efficiencies there that
are generally in when when processes and
growth of businesses are cheaper,
generally that's good for the world in
aggregate, right? So, maybe Apple's like
silently wising up to this. It's good
for them. It's good for developers. It's
probably good for the people involved
too. As long as that data isn't being
brokered a million ways to like a bunch
of, you know, do weird stuff, but I
think that's maybe not not the uh
not the primary case. And that's what
Apple broke with ATT. So, so I think
it's like they maybe achieved their
primary goal with ATT. And maybe this
kind of refutes previous conversations
about how Apple specifically did it to
break Facebook and to like cash in and
like build their own ad network. And
like there was all these like conspiracy
theories early on that that's why Apple
did it. But I've always maintained that
it genuinely was like a kind of privacy
fundamentalism inside of Apple. And they
did achieve like by deprecating the
IDFA, like it is way harder to like
build up a dossier on an individual user
across multiple apps. And so, Facebook
using fingerprinting internally to
Facebook is like not giving them
all this like super private data. And
Well, it's not like Facebook doesn't
have a dossier on all their users.
Yeah, they already have it. Yeah,
exactly.
what I mean? This is like we already
knew where you lived and who you dated,
but now we actually know what running
app you use. It's like it's like what's
the incremental damage at that point,
right?
And that's what's been so frustrating
about scan. It was like it was like
built from a like that privacy
fundamentalism standpoint of like we
can't let any any personal data leak.
And I think AEM is a good example of
like, hey, the economic value is there.
We should let companies like Facebook do
this to the benefit of our entire
platform. Also, the users users have
already engaged in like data private
data sharing with us cuz anyway, we're
very Yeah, yeah. We're We're probably
getting way off the rails here. But,
yeah, maybe this is a second podcast we
can do on just like the state of the the
state of the attribution industry. But,
I think we've hit all the I think we
kind of hit all the like major key
points for smaller apps. And And you
broke it up in And what Why is web to
app so different like treat looked at
differently when you get to scale? Like,
how does it change? I think the reason
it changes when you get to scale is not
because those benefits don't apply.
Everyone cares about cash flow. But,
typically,
the amount that these larger apps are
spending on ad spend is not the biggest
concern. Like, you know what I mean?
It's like they're not going to not be
able to do anything next month because
they had a little bit of a bad week.
Yeah, you also have access to capital,
typically. Like, you can get loans even
like it once you have some Once you're
established, it's just not as big a
deal. Exactly. So, I think cash flow
Sure, the fees become, you know, a
little bit more relevant. All of a
sudden, 30% hits a lot harder than 15.
Um so, I think, you know, that's that's
one thing. And even though, you know,
people say, "Yeah, but it's not It's not
30% forever." It's like, "Hey, this is a
new user, and I'm I'm not getting 30%
This is significant."
It is, essentially, when you're like
running a little bit of ad arbitrage,
right? You're like, "I'm not really able
to count on that next year's revenue,
anyway. So, thank you for that discount
from you know, it's like a Here's like
Here's a gift card for a discount next
year. Thank you, Apple." Exactly. So,
it's like, yeah, the fees become more of
a benefit Or, sorry, the fees become
more of an issue, and web to app becomes
more beneficial in that way. But, I
think the others that are more exciting
are kind of what you touched on earlier,
Jacob, around control. The ability to
really control the user journey and the
funnel as much as you possibly would
like to. And when I speak about this, I
mean kind of going back to the days of
here's a specific ad creative, which
happens to tie with this landing page,
which happens to tie with this
onboarding funnel. And guess what? The
paywall is exactly the same. And kind of
really building out a granular journey
based on the job to be done or problem
statements that top of funnel. You can
kind of still do a little bit more of
this now with, you know, custom product
pages and and these kind of
advancements. But, I don't think it's
the same, and I don't think it ever will
be because really what we want to do is
say, "Hey, this person saw this ad. So,
in onboarding, I want to ask them this
set of questions." Yeah, you can't have
a fully integrated like funnel as
product, right? Where it's like the ad
into the funnel, like it's all
integrated and reactive. You can't
really do that without something like
this. It's the synergy of acquisition
and product. That's what's missing.
Sure, we can have a really great top of
funnel synergy, ad creative, App Store
screenshots. Great. And then we can
learn about them in onboarding and
tailor the paywall. But, we can't
necessarily do the whole thing.
But, again, even that benefit that I
touched on that example was just
speaking around quizzes and kind of how
you may use that in a quiz funnel. But,
things like how you anchor pricing. I'm
sure everyone watching this has had an
app rejected at some point because they
had some sort of violation on their
paywall.
Right, price related, whatever it may
be. And And I think that is frustrating.
And also, there are sometimes things
that you want to do which you may not
think this isn't unethical. This is just
I want to anchor pricing this way. I
want to see how it performs.
And you don't really get any refunds or
any upset users from it, but Apple don't
like you doing certain things. So, I
think it kind of opens the floodgates on
that front.
And similarly, when we think about
things like money-back guarantees
instead of trials, right? This is
something what you just
I Funny enough, I actually saw in the
Sub Club community today someone posted
something about, "Hey, are people doing
this in app, and how are they doing
this?" I didn't read the post in its
entirety, but on the web, this is a big
thing. Yeah, Fay and the Dipsy team
internally here are try are are running
on the web a money-back guarantee
alternative to trial, which experiment,
yeah. So, I think there are all kinds of
things you can control that you can't
control in app. And back to your your
point on custom product pages, it's like
that's been kind of the biggest
innovation in like 16 years of the App
Store. I mean, if you think about the
fundamental user journey of the App
Store
across these 16 years, you dump somebody
into the App Store, they see three
screenshots, a description, a user icon.
Like, yeah, there's like discoverability
stuff, search has changed a little bit,
but like the fundamental experience of
the App Store is pretty much the same 16
years on. It's like three screen And
yeah, you can scroll and get more
screenshots, but what do people actually
see? How do you stand out? You know what
I mean? Like, I I I sometimes I open the
App Store, and I just like everything
looks like the same app slop. No offense
to all of my customers, but like you
just go And especially if you search
search like an AI keyword or something
like this, and it's just like every like
variant of slightly modified AI wrapper,
and you're just like you almost like
lose your mind. You're like, "I just
need I just want to be talked to, you
know what I mean? I don't want to scroll
through screenshots. I I want to like be
sold." So, having that control to
actually create an experience that's
somewhat differentiating, too. Cuz like
the likelihood I mean, I would This is I
don't want the data on this, but if
somebody clicks on an app ad, they
probably click on more than yours. You
know what I mean? Like, somebody who
clicks on app ads probably somebody who
clicks on app ads. And so, you have to
have something that's going to make them
be the one This is the one that they
convert on, right? Yeah, and then again,
speaking to control, like you were
talking earlier about getting rejected
for like pay pricing and paywall issues.
I got rejected for creating a video of
the widget in my weather app, and I
cropped it horizontally 16 by 9 of like
the home screen so that I could really
highlight a medium-size widget. And
Apple rejected me and said I had to
create a new video that was like
vertical so that it could represent the
entire home screen. I was like, "Look,
the widget is really small. If I crop it
horizontally, it still looks like a home
page, but you can actually see what's
going on." And they're like, "No, no,
no, you need a vertical video to show
off your horizontal widget." And it's
like dumb stuff like that where they
take control of stuff that like doesn't
matter, and they lock everything.
Anyway, I could rant for a long time
about it. But, to your point on control,
I mean, they they reject screenshots
every time. And parts of it I get, like,
you know, they do prevent a lot of
unscrupulous developers from
Unscrupulous developers from cropped
screenshots, you know? Well, but But,
there used to be stuff, and you know,
you don't hear about anymore because it
doesn't happen because they stop you
know, they don't allow developers to do
this. But, there used to be issues with
people putting screenshots that were
just totally fake. I mean, it's like
these fake ads for games. There is
consumer value in Apple
having some level of like being able to
reject stuff. This is always their
problem, though. It's like it's not the
intention, but it's always when they
scale it. Same with App Review. Like,
it's like how do you How do you teach a
thousand entry-level employees to like
adjudicate App Store pages? It's very,
very hard. When we speak about web to
app, it's not that everyone's making the
shift from in app to web to app so that
they can be unscrupulous and have all
these unethical thing They're doing it
because they want a horizontal video.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Exactly. Yeah,
yeah. Exactly.
Like, that video is a better sell for my
app than anything I can do in a
screenshot, but Apple won't let me It's
just Apple's You know, I mean, they're
to Apple's view, and I think they're
somewhat right here. The App Store is
their These are their users, and they
feel they have a duty to protect them,
and they've made certain promises about
what you'll get on the App Store. And
you know, it's This is the deal we've
made, right? We give you 30%, and you
get to insult us. But, but
But, it's fine, right? But, but, but, I
mean, I don't want to I don't want to
jinx it because like I think Apple like
This is again zooming out a little bit,
but they it's relevant to this part of
the conversation, but they've more or
less been okay with this kind of stuff.
I think this might go into the AM
conversation as well. Like, Apple kind
of turns an eye to like a certain amount
of things. As long as you're playing
ball in the things that they control, as
long as you're not being a total like a
total rake and just like doing
unscrupulous stuff constantly. Like,
Apple I mean, they won't say officially
they're cool with this, but like by
their in lack of action They've never
taken action against it. They've
essentially like implied that they're
okay with this, which I think is great.
You know, I think they I think there is
some level of understanding there. They
got to do what they got to do. They got
to lock down what they have to for their
own like sort of messaging. But, then
they do understand that these things are
important, and they really are helping
the app economy and things like this.
So, And I think ultimately, this whole
web to app movement is great for
developers in the long run because as
more and more developers find more and
more success outside of the App Store
using web payments, Apple has to do
something Has to respond, yeah, at some
point. Yeah, it's like they need to like
evolve their thinking on the App Store,
or more and more and more and more and
more traffic is just going to go to the
web. All right, we've hammered on
control. But, Nathan's got a bunch of
really good points here, and I want to
make sure we give them adequate time.
So, what else What else for big apps is
one of the the benefits? Reaching new
audiences, right? Expanding your reach.
I think is massive massive. And I think
this takes It takes so many forms. I
think the obvious one Or not the obvious
one, but the one that Thomas mentioned,
David, when you spoke to him on the
podcast, around reaching different
pockets of audiences on existing
channels. I think it's a great one that
a lot of people still aren't really
aware of. Is that when I pick app
promotion campaign, install campaign,
I'm getting a different pocket of users
than if I pick app promotion campaign,
trial start as my event, which then
becomes completely different again if I
select a sales campaign and a conversion
campaign on web. Because, to your point,
Jacob, if I'm clicking on an app ad, I'm
probably clicking on multiple. There are
people out there who don't click on app
ads, but do click on web ads. And
therefore, if I want to reach those
users on a given channel, I need to use
a different campaign type and campaign
objective, which is one layer of
expansion. But, I think it really goes
even deeper than that. For example, I
like to think of expansion to do with
intent. When you are pushing traffic to
the app, you are if you take a
subscription app, focused so focused on
can we get this person to start a trial
to send back the trial event to meta.
Can we use a hard paywall and get the
purchase event to go back to meta? And
sure you can optimize a funnel that way
and you can reach profitability and have
something that works, but there are a
whole load of users that are dropping
off and we we never think about those
that didn't make it. The guy who
downloaded the app but didn't start the
trial. What happens to him? Like he's
gone, right? We didn't get any data on
him. Sign up was after the paywall. I
don't know, he's gone. But we still paid
for those impressions, right? Now with
web, you can have a lot more lead
magnets, you can capture lower intent
traffic, blog articles and webinars like
we spoke about. You do retargeting,
right? Like after Yeah. Not even on the
primary channel that you attracted them
initially, right? You can have other
networks you're running to do
retargeting once once somebody's at
least gotten to your gotten to your
funnel. Precisely. So when it comes to
kind of building out a full stack
multi-channel approach, you can do a lot
more on web. And I think that is really
big for a lot of apps who are spending a
lot already, right? They're already
juicing the spend. They're looking for
new things. Like what can I do now?
Well, maybe now you should invest in
some long-form content and some lead
magnets and really start to nurture
those that aren't going to purchase
today or tomorrow or next week, but
probably will in 2 months time.
That's more like a B2B motion, right?
Where it's like, you know, start to
think about a consumer you're always
initially targeting just like these like
fleeting moments of intent or trying to
like manufacture intent in a in a very
narrow moment. And B2B like we're
constantly just doing the latter or what
what you just described anything which
is where it's like just be ever present
because we don't know when that moment's
going to happen necessarily, but we just
need to like cover the zone. Yeah, I
guess like at scale it probably makes
sense. I mean, you think about this too
like at least Duolingo at a a very broad
example, but just think they weren't
doing brand marketing 10 years ago, you
know what I mean? Like now they had just
have weird videos with the owl that go
viral and like there's nothing about
their app at all, right? It's just like
you just need to be thinking about the
owl constantly, right? And it works. But
it doesn't work until you're at a
certain amount of scale, right? Which
yeah, to your to your point is kind of
the the evolving benefits in web to app
as you grow. Can you give some like
specific examples that you've seen work
well whether it's like web, Google
search, or YouTube, or or maybe even go
through multiple kind of flows and
channels that you think do a good job of
capturing some of that intent that
you're not going to capture directing
people straight through the app store
into the app? Absolutely. So one example
was a project I worked on where we ended
up building out an entire webinar funnel
to push a subscription app. Now it
wasn't like a $30 a year subscription,
it was like 200 pounds a year. So it
was, you know, it was fairly high ticket
for a subscription app. But the
challenge was it was a pretty sensitive
topic and people just weren't ready
emotionally to invest in that kind of
purchase at the time. So you're hitting
home, the message resonates, absolutely
I hear you, but I'm not ready for this.
I need some time.
So we can't we can't run app We can, but
then we have to go into freemium and
that's like a whole other thing. We
didn't want to do that. We wanted to
scale up top of funnel as fast as we
could.
Well, you actually kind of created a
freemium, right? It's like you created
an a free on-ramp that doesn't
necessarily wasn't the app, but you're
like, okay, here's some value before you
purchase, right? And that was
pushed three ways. You two ways really.
Meta, Instagram, Facebook, but also
YouTube. And I think this is where it
becomes really interesting because we
could just take portions of that video
and edits of that video, upload them to
YouTube, run them as YouTube ads, and
then direct people to watch the
full-length webinar. Oh, okay. So you
would take clips from the webinar and
then Oh, so interesting. It wasn't live.
It was like a Yeah, more like a VSL,
like a masterclass. Okay. And so they
would what? They would have to like sign
up or something or some gating to get to
it? Yeah, we experimented with a few
different things. The gating works. You
can nowadays you can kind of make it
seem as though it's live. So you can
have people, you know, a webinar that
starts every 5 minutes. You're like, I
just I just made it. Oh, that's that's
tricky.
I'm already having FOMO though. I guess
at that point, I mean, webinar but this
is generally just like a piece of free
low commitment content that you're
giving away a lot of value to the
customer, right? Do you even in the in
those lead-in ads, do you advertise the
app at all or was it purely just like,
hey, here's a webinar on this topic?
Yeah, no no mention of the app. More
like this is the topic you're struggling
with, this is the solution. Yeah, which
goes back to your expansion thing,
right? It's like, okay, there's not not
everybody is somebody who thinks of an
app. I think about like my my parents'
generation, I'm constantly pitching apps
to them
and they're like, "App? What's an app
going to do?" And it's like apps can
solve a lot of problems, okay? And then
I'm like, "Okay, just let me download
the app." And then they're like, 2 days
later, "I subscribed to this app. I
know, I got premium forever pro or
whatever." And it's like, "Of course you
did. Of course you did. You just had to
be open to it, right?" I mean, I think
that's probably this part of this
expansion story is there is just like a
lot of people who they miss the the
boat. I see it in myself as like new
technologies are coming out as I
approach 40 and like new tech is coming
out that the Gen Alpha Gen Z said is
using and I'm like, "Ugh, you know, I
don't want that. I don't need that in my
life." And I have no reason to resist
that other than I'm other than it's like
I didn't witness it coming up, right? So
like I've heard this from a couple folks
I've talked to web to app. It's just
like you get access to a whole new
audience of people who will watch a
webinar but won't download an app
download an app. Will take a quiz but
won't download an app, right? And you
get an opportunity to pitch them.
Obviously your conversions are going to
be all wacky. It's going to be a totally
different machine. But at scale we're
talking about at scale here is like you
need to always be looking for that next
card you can play. Like, okay, what's
the next frontier? And so that's really
cool. I bet if people put the thought
they could probably come up with a lot
of a lot of really cool ideas for like
how do I build something that's a little
bit less than just get into my app, get
a free trial or just get into my app and
try the freemium, but it's like what can
I build on the internet? look I mean,
this podcast is an example, right?
There's like we've done this kind of
intentionally unintentionally just
giving away a lot of value, but like
thinking about how we do it at scale or
how an app would do it at scale for
that, you know, that's slightly lower
ticket value is kind of very
interesting. Yeah, and I think the
interesting thing about this example is
we weren't even at scale when we tried
this. Oh, so it was just like from the
start? Yeah, it was it was more to do
with
the audience needed more time to convert
and we needed a fast trial start if we
wanted to get our post back. So we were
kind of at conflict. Also, the audience
was slightly older. So the other, you
know, we're talking about expanding
audiences, you can also expand it to
different age demographics. Desktop.
A lot of people still do use Facebook on
their desktop and you can reach them via
the web. So things like this, but you
mentioned that your parents didn't want
to download an app. Probably if they
came through a web to app journey and
they landed on a website, they may have
felt differently.
So there are different different plays.
Especially if they were like an
influencer involved, right? Somebody
they like respects or like watch on TV,
you know what I mean? Or something like
this. They might just like slow walk
them from what they're comfortable with
into like something that maybe is
uncomfortable for them. I think it's
it's really fascinating. And it like
plays back into control cuz it's like
once a developer has the control on
this, the world is their oyster. They
can try all kinds of stuff, right? Max
Weinberg, the founder of DuckDuckGo, has
this really wonderful book on growth.
We'll put it in the show notes. I can't
think of the name of it, but he's like
he he contends that there's only like
seven different growth tricks, right?
It's like PR, paid marketing, SEO,
whatever. I always thought it was really
painful because in the app world you can
only do like two of the seven, you know?
It's like paid ads and SEO on the app
store. It's about it. But this actually
opens up like basically every channel
now, right? That you can try and you can
try programmatically which is just it's
just really cool. Not only every
channel, but like a ton of creativity
because it's it's not just sending
people to the app store page and making
that funnel work. It's like talking
through this has got me really excited.
I had not thought about web to app quite
so broadly as you're presenting it and
it's genuinely making me excited in that
I talk to so many developers who are
like, "How do we get those first 500
downloads?" And when you're trying to
push people to the app store and there's
low intent and maybe you like I said
earlier, maybe they got a 3.5 star on
the app store currently because of
whatever 1.0 issues. And like this just
the world is your oyster as an app if
you think about it in this way any form
of and it like the web marketing is like
15 years ahead of app marketing in
tooling and like so many different ways
and so it just opens up so many
possibilities to shape that entire
funnel. So yeah, it's super exciting to
think about it more broadly like this.
Any other like top of mind examples of
like cool things that you would never
think would work for an app that you're
seeing work for an app? I think it
becomes interesting because now we get
into how you're building out the web
funnel or the web onboarding journey.
There are some things you can do with
web apps that you can't do with
WordPress. Let's put it this way, right?
So I guess an an example is I want to
take a picture of the food in front of
me and it's going to tell me with some
clever AI how many calories in the food.
You can build that demo into a web
journey. Now you can also build it into
the app, but now I can bring it super
early. So I can experiment with ads that
just take people directly to some tool
to take a picture of food and give me
calories. Would I do that? Only at real
scale when I don't care about
conversion, but if I bake that
functionality into some sort of cohesive
journey, for example, you know, I'm
pushing calorie tracking and
macronutrients and I have people sign up
or not and then I say, "Hey, are you
eating now?" And people say yes or are
you near food? Yeah. Let's play a game.
Take a picture of the food and we'll
demo the product. It's so much smoother
on web because you're already asking for
a lot of There's already a lot of
friction there, right? I'm asking
someone to go to their fridge and open
it up and take picture of food or or
something like this. But if it's no sign
up, nothing's gated, and it kind of
feels like a fun thing to do, some users
are going to do this. And you know,
there are apps doing stuff like this,
which you can you can like try. So, I
think those are kind of the more product
demo experiences that you can build out
on web, but they are, in my opinion,
super fun because it then becomes what
functionality does that app do, and how
can we rebuild part of this on the web
to decrease time to value. So, another
interesting opportunity on the web is
that you're not as constrained to what
you sell even. So, inside an app, it's
typically just a digital purchase only,
and you can't have any add-ons. So, tell
me about the opportunities to diversify
things you sell and to increase average
revenue per user on the web.
I mean, the obvious example are things
like upsells. But I think where it gets
smart is when you have things like
one-click upsells. I've already taken
their payment details. I'm now going to
show them something that's an add-on,
and they're going to click buy.
Or you can bundle products with your
subscription. So, it's almost like a a
cross-sell pre-purchase, right? We're
just We're just bundling products,
whether that be, you know, you're a
fitness app and you also have some
fitness clothing that you want to bundle
on, or you want to sell a nutrition
guide. One great example are apps where
you take photos or like, you know,
family photos, and we're going to sell
send you physical albums and photo
albums, stuff like this. That can work
really well on web. These kind of
upsells, I don't see too many people
using them. Like, you know, Noom,
Headway, they do have upsells. Often
times a lot of people are still using
digital upsells, though. But there are
some edge cases where you can actually
bundle physical products and ship them.
So, yeah, the family albums one example.
Is it Headway shipping like physical
books now? Like I think they might do.
Yeah, they might be. I think the idea of
bundling digital content is really
interesting, right? Because like you're
Most of these businesses are already
digital businesses, right? And so like
when you're thinking about increasing
your revenue or your LTV, as David was
pointing out, I mean, you could in
theory You know what? Honestly, it's
just the it's the point of purchase
friction. Like as you were saying,
Nathan, like, you know, if you want to
like, okay, get into the payment
details, like you can craft that
experience such that you collect payment
details, you get authorization, and then
like you right before checkout, you're
like, "Hey, why don't you add this
extra, you know, if you're a fitness
class, like here's a like exclusive like
VOD option, right? For another another
piece of content." Or like, you know,
you got something with a problem, and
all of this is like, you know, it's just
like trying to find how painful this is
for the person and like also just sort
of what their price sensitivity is, like
what their value line is, right? I
actually think bundling is a really one
of the challenges and one of the
challenges in B2C always is just like
price discrimination or essentially like
finding out how much money like
somebody, you know, like finding a right
price for somebody so that you can kind
of have a good like sort of value
extraction with your value with your
value creation for them. And that's sort
of a clean In gaming, they do it by just
letting you buy more coins or like make
purely a consumption mechanic, but by
adding some other like SKUs that you can
like bundle on, I think it's a really
good idea. And then, you know, with
anything, doing it at the point of
purchase, like there's often just like a
lot of intent and a lot of, you know,
you're very up funnel still. So, you get
more eyeballs and things like that. But
I can see like that being complex,
right? And why you wouldn't want to try
this until you're very late stage. But
familiarity as well. Like, this is not
new. Amazon does this. Oh, they get me
all the time. Customers also bought. I'm
like, "Yeah, I need that, too." I I
didn't know I needed tape. I do need
tape. Thank you. Click, you know. It's
always the most generic items. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. But it works on me. Like, I
What was I buying the other day? I don't
know. I was buying some electronics
stuff, and they were like, "Do you
probably need some more solder?" And I
was like, "Yeah, you know what? I'm
actually out of solder. I'll just go
ahead and add that." It's a little bit
different here, right? Obviously, it's
very But I still think the concept, you
know, there's a reason stores stuff the
checkout aisle. You know what I mean?
With like sort of useful, but maybe like
stuff you wouldn't necessarily go out of
your way to buy. But yeah, the
complexity of implementing that, I
think, is, you know, probably probably
doesn't make it worth the squeeze until
Also, you have a brand, right? Like, you
know, I've heard of Noom. I've heard my
friends have used it and whatever, and
I've decided to go all in or whatever.
And then getting offered like some sort
of upsell at that point of purchase is
probably different than random app I've
never even heard of ever trying to sell
me another thing that I just, you know
what I mean? So, it's probably just a
card you have to judiciously like choose
when you play. It can probably thwart
user intent as much as it can expand the
ARPU. So, probably something to be
careful of. And then it I mean, that
kind of thinking easily turn into a dark
pattern, too. My wife went through a a
web flow where there was just continue
buttons, continue, continue, continue,
and she got to the end not realizing
that those continue buttons were
actually adding stuff to the cart, and
there wasn't like a final checkout that
like gave a full dollar amount. You know
who's really bad at this is the travel
industry. They're really bad at it,
right? It's like, "Oh, insurance." And
no, the extra premium. Like airlines are
terrible. I mean, they all cuz it works,
I guess, but like, yeah, they're all
terrible at it. Nathan, I want to I want
to ask like sort of related to ARPU, but
maybe more like LTV of a install
generally. But are there like general
like characteristics or sort of about
the way that people buy? You know, it's
credit card, it's not the App Store. Are
LTVs like generally lower, generally
higher? Like churns? Like how do you
think about the quality of these
customers? Are there any sort of
expectations people should have before
they start this? It's a great question,
and it's hard to answer directly because
of the dark patterns.
Yeah, if you have a dark pattern, really
high. Yeah, it's like a lot of people
are, as you were saying, doing these
things on web where it's like, "Oh,
look, web's working really well." Like,
I guess an easy example, which maybe
this isn't so dark, but whether it be a
free trial or paid trial with a really
high annual price plan, just not
notifying them at all, not sending any
comms during the trial window, and then
just billing them at the end. It's like,
"Oh, you've already got payment
details." If it's especially if it's a
paid trial, it's really easy to do that,
but questionable. So, typically, LTV is
higher on web. Aside from these things,
is it higher? I'm not sure. I mean, It
probably depends. Just what you're
selling and what price point and and and
all of that stuff. I've heard from some
folks uh some of the mechanics of like
the apps like working with credit cards,
some of the Like, for example, you
mentioned paid trials, which I think is
much more common web to app. The reason
being I've heard is just there's so many
fake credit cards. People like have
credit cards that either bounce or
they're not real or whatever. They use
those to access a credit card locked
free trial. And I know one developer I
spoke to, at least like they started
with a free trial, and then they
converted to like a $1 one-month trial,
right? So, it's essentially a trial, but
it's a really an intro period. And that
has the benefit of you've now validated
this is a real credit card, and it costs
money, which then you're just saving
yourself the pain of like providing
service to those users, and then like
you know, having a failed credit card.
Probably net it maybe doesn't make a big
difference, but it does like kind of
help with some of those conversion
rates. I've also heard a lot, and I'm
I'm curious if you've heard the same,
just like about It's kind of all the
stuff that we grouse about. We complain
about the App Store fee a lot, but then
once you're like dealing with credit
cards and direct payment, you realize
like, "Well, okay, this is kind of
nice." Because one, yeah, there's just
like, you know, Visa and all these have
these different sort of like rules
around I think it's called 3D Secure.
There's like different things you can do
that will like increase the likelihood
that payments go through, but then also
reduce your exposure to fraud stuff. So,
like if there's a lot of fraudulent
credit cards being used on your site,
you're liable for that. And people like
Stripe will They They are also liable to
provide some protection to Visa for
that. And depending on what payment
provider you're using, so you now have
to think about that, which isn't
necessarily something you have to think
about on the App Store. I mean, you do.
Like people do get kicked off the App
Store for like a lot of fraudulent
transactions. I think Visa and the App
Store, one, they have to deal with the
chargebacks. So, like, you know, when
people are getting ripped off, Visa has
to eat that. And if they have a vendor
who's, you know, seems like you're
getting a lot of chargebacks, they're
going to kick you off. But then also
there's like things like money
laundering and stuff that can happen.
People use these sort sort of flows for
that that people have to watch out for,
which I think generally on the App
Store, you don't have to think about.
But for web to app, it's now something
that you're going to have to get good
at. And the folks I've talked to that
have gotten successful, at least some
percentage of them had to go through
sort of this process of understanding
what these like sort of finer points
are. It becomes a lot messier, right?
And I think that's why you know, even
you didn't touch on it, but I thought
you were going there, like chargebacks,
right? Refunds, handling these yourself
as opposed to having the benefit of
Apple. Yeah, even just the mechanics of
it, right? Like where does a user go to
get a refund? You have to have that
figured out somewhere, right? Right in
the App Store, it's taken care of for
you.
What tooling are you using, and like how
do you approach that when you're setting
this up with the clients that you work
with? I think the first thing comes into
Are you using Stripe? Like, everyone
defaults to Stripe because they're so
big. But when I look at the different
options, Paddle is really solid for a
lot of things, right? They have a lot of
great tools for sales tax compliance,
which we haven't even touched on, but
that's another thing to be considered.
Yeah, so they they buffer at least some
of the risk for you. You know, fraud,
things like this. So, that's really kind
of where to start. Beyond this, I've
been fortunate that some of the bigger
clients that we've worked with have
already been fully on top of this and
aware of it. I don't think it's such a
big issue for smaller apps, either,
right? Like, no one really has to worry
about that much fraud if you've only got
15 paying customers a week. It's like
probably it's legit, but I think it's an
area where there's almost a gap. There's
almost a gap for tooling or a gap for
for mobile apps. Yeah, they have it all.
Cuz it's it's a lot of And this is, you
know, it was probably no secret that
we're keen on this space and like trying
to figure out and trying to build our
way there. And these conversations this
one, obviously, but then I've had
conversations with a lot of founders
this year that have been doing this
stuff. And yeah, it's the payments
complexity we were just talking about.
All of the stuff we've been talking
about is software, right? It's like you
got websites, and you got quizzes, and
you got landing pages. And each of those
individually is kind of probably a
simple thing, but then you have to If
you want it to work, we're talking about
synergies between your acquisition and
product and all that stuff, you want it
to be all stitched together, and the
complexity can get quite hairy over
time. We've definitely seen there's like
a number of like upstarts trying to work
on this stuff. And I expect that to
probably continue into 2025. Hopefully
we can revenue I can get a decent
solution, but you know, baby steps.
Sometimes we take it slow so we can take
it fast. But yeah, I think like I think
it's clear, at least from what I'm
talking about, it's not necessarily like
slam dunk value for everybody, but like
it's definitely worth trying, right? At
some stage, for sure. So we've gone
through a lot of the complexity, the
benefits, some drawbacks, but kind of a
higher level, how should people be
thinking about that? They're listening
to this podcast, and they're thinking,
"Okay, we should do web to app." What
are the questions people should be
asking themselves to get started? Yeah,
I think it's a great question. And the
questions they should be asking are
really, "Why do we want to do web to
app?" I think this is why I always I
always ask clients and potential clients
first is, "Why is this appealing to
you?"
Is it because of the fees? Like And
often times it's like, "Yeah, I heard
that like we'll save money."
And then it's a case of figuring out
that there's there's more to it than
just the fees, because you need to
actually be profitable on web. And you
don't know whether the traffic is going
to be more expensive or not. So we've
got to try all this out. We've got to
build landing pages and funnels that
convert. So it's it's not as simple as
just switching two buttons on an ads
platform. But that's the first question.
Is it, "Why do you want to do this?" The
other question I'd like to ask is, "What
does your existing marketing funnel look
like? Like how are you converting at the
moment in app?" Because the best place
to start on web is that.
For example, if you have a really long
onboarding in app
build it on web. That's where you should
start. If you're a utility app and you
have a hard paywall don't build a long
quiz on web. Like I've had some like
utility app founders I asked me, "I'm
really struggling to come up with like
questions to ask on the web." Oh my god,
there's such a great meta note about
founder cargo cult thing there. And I
think that's like some message we try to
tell in this podcast always, which is
like don't listen to anybody Nathan's
great. Everybody we have on this podcast
great, but don't listen to anybody like
without thinking about your situation
because like
I mean, it's obvious, but I don't know.
Everybody wants to make more money, they
want to try stuff, so it's like, "Okay,
how do you feel about multiply and
divide for my calculator app?" You know
what I mean? Like what's your feelings?
Like how are you hoping to improve your
ability to find the area of a room? Very
funny. Yeah, exactly. And I think, you
know, that's the place to start. And
then I think specifically when it comes
to then building out long onboarding
funnels it becomes questions like, "What
is it?" Most people who are already
running successful in app onboarding
journey duplicate that on web and see
some sort of success.
Very rarely have we ever worked with an
app where they have a solid profitable
in app onboarding funnel, they mirror
that on web, and it just doesn't work.
Like that's not the case. Often times
there are certain questions that we want
to remove or certain things we need to
add in, like certain problem statements
we want to hit a little bit more and
kind of change the funnel based on the
traffic. But generally speaking, if it's
working in app it's the same target
market, it's the same. They don't really
care that much that it's web, right?
It's not It's just a screen with stuff
they can read on it. So I think that's
one question. Another question would be,
well, which is a big one, "How much do
we want to invest before we give up on
this or not?" I think a lot of teams are
focused on building product and getting
that existing funnel working. So the
appeal of web to app sounds great, but
the investment required to actually get
it working, not so much, especially with
the lack of tooling to make web to app
fast. And then obviously there are some
products out there that help make it
fast, but there's nothing that really
does it end to end super quick, doesn't
require any dev resource. We're great.
So I think any app team that's going to
start investing web to app is going to
need to allocate one time, two
resources, and three money. Probably you
should be very cautious about diluting
your spend that's going to the app and
try and bring new spend into the web,
depending on where you're at. If you're
spending millions and millions in app,
sure you can just slash some of that and
send it to web. But if you're only
spending enough to reach learning phases
and privacy thresholds in app, you're
going to need to make a decision because
that becomes a little bit complex.
So yeah, those are some considerations I
think most teams should ask before
launching this. Yeah, and to your point
earlier, I do think it's interesting
that if you're an app that has a few
hundred people coming in, like you've
got the product flywheel going, jumping
to web instead of really dialing in that
product market fit and getting that
first motion going seems like it can
just be a distraction that's actually
going to net you less in the long run,
even if you save a little bit on fees,
even if you get a little more kind of
cost advantage. But I like what you're
saying earlier, and I hadn't thought
about it from this like standpoint, if
you're struggling to start that product
motion
and you've got a product going, but you
just don't have people getting getting
into it, like then maybe it is worth the
investment just to get that zero to one
motion going. Yeah, there's almost like
a middle there where it's probably If
your app's kind of working and you kind
of have something, you should probably
just focus there until you hit
headwinds. But if you're very at the
very very beginning or if you're at the
very kind of like late stage on the app
like core app, you can maybe think about
it. It's kind of an interesting reality.
I don't know, it's probably varies, but
like what kind of mixes of folks Folks
that have done this successfully for
some period, I guess like I guess like
as a percentage of like net new
subscribers, like what percentages of
people's traffic are coming revenue-wise
like coming from web to app in a good
setup? It varies, right? Like 80/20,
20/80, 50/50. Oh really, all over the
map. It really just depends, which is an
argument for maybe it should work It
could work for you, right? But I think
it could be any one of those, right? It
could only be a minority. It's not that
dissimilar to like some of the like pre
We wouldn't call it web to app, but like
adding a Stripe online conversion
through email follow-up campaign. You
know what I mean? These are not like
going to change your life, but they are
like incremental improvements on
retention and conversion that you should
do. But again, not before you have like
a core funnel that's kind of working. I
think it also comes down to as well what
people are able to get working first.
For example, a lot of people will start
with web and app, see that web's
working, and then scale web more so that
it makes up a higher percentage of
overall net new revenue. That's just
because you've scaled that more. Like
it's not to say that there's a big
opportunity there. Yeah, yeah, which is
often the case, too. And yeah, anytime
you're evaluating businesses in sort of
like a snapshot, people want to draw too
many conclusions about like why numbers
are a certain way, and like often it's
like, "Well, that's just cuz this is how
it This is this moment in time, you
know." As we start to wrap up, I did
want to kind of do a little bit of a
quick fire and maybe hit on some of your
like top practical tips. Like if you're
going to make this work, here are some
of the things you should try. And I do
actually want to start with like
verticals. Like are there like specific
kinds of apps, specific kinds of intent
that you think are going to have a
higher likelihood of succeeding and
others where you think, like we were
joking about a calculator app, but like
that's maybe a good example of like
probably going to struggle. Like people
are looking for that utility on their
phone, they're probably willing to
download an app. Like they're probably
verticals that just really shouldn't try
or maybe should delay web to app until
they're way further along in their
journey. So how do you think about
those? Yeah, I think you hit the nail on
the head. Utility apps don't need to
invest in web to app. That doesn't mean
it can't work. A lot of people think
utility apps just can't make web to app
work. They can't make quizzes work in a
lot of cases because there's nothing you
need to ask users. But they can most
definitely have landing page checkout,
here's the product. And that can work
well. Just like they'll have
screenshots, paywall, native front. If
it solves a problem. And like is like I
think a flighty, like that's kind of a
utility app. You know what I mean? Like
and I could imagine easily converting
people from the web if you were
targeting it correctly. But yeah, I
wouldn't ask a quiz about your travel.
You know what I mean? Maybe I would,
actually. How often do you travel? Cuz
flighty's one of these apps that gets
way better the more you travel, right?
So like kind of building I
Okay, never mind. Utilities, you should
do a quiz for your calculator. I changed
my mind. Don't listen to me. Don't
listen to me. Listen to me instead.
Well, yeah, don't do that. Okay.
Official advice from Nathan, he's a
smart one. Don't don't do that. Okay.
But yeah, and then in terms of intent,
low intent web. High intent, maybe not
web. In the If there's low intent, you
need longer time to convert, you need to
put more effort in. You can do a lot
more in web. It goes back into what we
were speaking about about control.
But I generally like to say that there
aren't that many verticals that
shouldn't try web to app. You should try
it as long as you have a hypothesis
around what you expect to happen or what
you're hoping to get out of this.
Again, touching on the intent piece,
blog posts, webinar funnels, gated lead
magnets, you can't really do these
things in app, and they really lend
themselves towards, you know, traffic
that's low intent or lower intent than
those that would want to purchase. So I
think that's that's one case.
The other thing I would say is around
pricing and price point. Typically I've
seen a lot of higher ticket products
make web work before app. Just And I
think it's for a range of reasons.
Sometimes it can be to do with the
audience, like the audience age, and how
comfortable they are purchasing on web
versus in app. Sometimes, you know, it
can be around just not being
comfortable, regardless of age, to spend
that much money on a subscription app,
more comfortable making those larger
purchases on web.
But again, low ticket subscription apps
work really well in app. You don't need
to necessarily invest all of this money
into building out web funnels just to
push your $29.99 annual product. Yeah.
Next up in our quick fire, what ad
channels are you seeing find success?
Any ad channel, or are there specific
ones you think work especially well?
Yeah, I think a lot of channels work.
I've seen meta work, Google like search
and YouTube, TikTok. I would say outside
of channels, affiliates and influencers
amazing with web. Again, it comes back
to the attribution piece. If I'm working
with influencers and creators and I want
them to push my product, it's hard to
attribute when it's mobile. On web, I
can just send them to a dedicated
landing page, UTM parameters, perfect.
So, I think it's not just kind of ad
channels but just channels more broadly
applicable for web to app. But I've not
come across a channel that just hasn't
worked. I know Top Thomas was saying he
hasn't like had that much success with
YouTube as a channel. I have, but that's
because the videos we were pushing were
like more long-form and it worked really
well. So again, I think it it depends,
but what I would say is don't think oh,
I'm I'm testing web, so now I need to
find a new channel. It should be
firstly, can we get existing channels
working on web? Secondly, are there
channels like this channel that we can
expand into? Thirdly, are there channels
unlike this channel that we should test?
Awesome. So next up, what data do you
feed back to the networks for improving
that targeting? In app, we talked about
how hard it is to get the right signals
and get it fed back and cross the
privacy thresholds. At least you don't
have to cross the privacy thresholds,
but what are you feeding back to the
networks and how are you making that
kind of targeting work on web? It's not
that dissimilar to mobile. The only
difference is we want to send as many
events as we can because we can map out
more of a funnel. So, we can send sign
up events, trial start events. We can
send multiple events and just kind of
see the conversion through each step.
So, that's one thing. You can also
experiment with optimizing for value as
opposed to just events. So, if you're
pushing, you know, monthly plans, annual
plans, lifetime plans, you can kind of
maximize value and send that data back,
which is something that some people are
doing, but it's not been talked spoken
about that much. I've tried it and it's
interesting. I I kind of don't have any
impressive results to share as of yet,
but I'm hopeful that we can get this
working. But yeah, really the same
things I would say to anyone looking to
launch on, you know, app promotion
campaigns. Make sure you're optimizing
for something that's actually valuable.
So, if the most valuable thing you can
optimize for is a trial start, then do
that. If it's the purchase, then do
that. But pixel tracking, step one. With
meta, you can use your conversions API
to send data from the back end, server
to server. Definitely, definitely do
that. Yeah, awesome. And then you had a
list. I didn't get to attend your
workshop at Growth Annual, but I got to
to see your slides. And so you had a a
list. I just want to quick-fire these
and just give me, you know, 90 seconds
on each of these. And this is like
specific tactics for creating a winning
web to app funnel. You've talked about
quizzes, but like what makes a good quiz
work on the web? Or even in app?
So, I think where quizzes are concerned,
I find this quite funny because quizzes
are all about ask asking questions,
right? We're asking questions to the
user. But an onboarding journey is about
us conveying value to the user. And it's
really about us answering their
questions. So, if you think about it,
the user has in their mind, is this app
going to work? Is it for people like me?
Is it going to do this, this, and this?
But what about this? They have all these
questions and we approach it with let me
ask my 15 questions so I can track them
nicely. The first thing I would say is
don't focus on what questions you're
asking, but focus on what questions
you're answering. Sometimes you can
answer a question with a question. For
example, if you land on Calm and you're
like, I don't know what this app does.
And then they say, are you here to
sleep, improve focus, etc. You now
understand what the app does. And
they've done that by asking a question
and giving you multiple choice answers.
But beyond that, you can use I like to
call them interludes, which are kind of
the screens that break up questions to
communicate specific information. I
think there are three types of content
you could put on an interlude, like
evidence, things that prove you do what
you say you do, whether that be charts,
graphs, social proof, testimonials, the
sorts.
Content that focuses on reassuring the
user. There may be known anxieties that
they have. I think there's a great
example from Headway that's like, do you
often worry? Or something like this,
like how often do you worry? And then
you click a lot and then it tells you,
hey, don't worry, loads of people worry,
stuff like this. That's an example of
reassuring the user. But the idea is you
want to figure out prior to building
what those are and then on certain
screens, call them out specifically. A
great example is time to value. I don't
know how long it's going to take for me
to get my abs. Summer's next week. Can I
do it? This app told me I can. Woohoo.
So the the charts we see. But that's one
and the final one is I would say
functionality. I don't not talk about
your product. You want them to get to
the end of onboarding and have a pretty
good understanding of what you're going
to do and how. So that's that's
something. And doing those things
ultimately adds value. Um so that's kind
of my my approach.
I guess if I had to wrap it up in a nice
way, I would say that a good web
onboarding journey tells a story. A
great web onboarding journey echoes
their story back to them. Next up is
social proof. How do you incorporate
social proof effectively and then how
effective is it and should people be
using social proof? I often get asked
what type of social proof should we use?
And I think it really comes down to what
questions, back to the previous comment,
the users have in their head. Like are
they thinking, do I believe this works?
Are they thinking, is this safe? Are
they think if it's like a a very
health-oriented product, you're asking
for medical information, is this a
trusted product? Who's validated this?
Who approves them? You know, whatever
these kind of questions are. But the
idea is what objections do people have?
Once you identify those, then you can
narrow down what social proof you should
be displaying on your paywall, not your
paywall, your web onboarding journey or
your paywall. I think a great example
is, and you've probably seen it all the
time, when people have like 80 million,
20 million, 30 million users use this
product. It's like, that's great, but
probably if 20, 50, 80 million people
use the product, I already know what the
product is. So, smaller apps who are
then like, join thousands of people
using my app. It's like,
doesn't really have the same the same
impact. You're better off saying, join
others who have XYZ like you and then
having a testimonial of someone just
like you who solved that problem. It's
less focused on kind of volume and and
quantity, more focused on kind of
qualitative efforts. And lastly, talk to
me about personalization. How, when, why
should you think about personalizing?
And then this does get to a point where
it can get very complex to personalize a
web journey where you've got this like
infinite branches of a of a tree, but I
know it can be powerful. So tell me
about how you think about
personalization. Yeah, I think
personalization is super key.
I think the reason it's so important is
because
it's how you echo their story back to
them. If I just have a really nice flow
and ask some great questions, I'm saying
stuff and I'm doing stuff, but I don't
know how relevant it is to you.
What I want to do is make you believe
that this product was designed for you.
Like someone sat down and thought about
David and then built the app.
And the way to do that is to ask
questions,
use the answers in the next questions,
and kind of take them on that journey.
What I would say though is that you
don't need to over-invest in this at the
beginning because often times the
diminishing returns are very real and
you think that adding way more
personalization is going to dramatically
increase your conversion rate and it
doesn't because people don't care that
much. So, I think the question is to
figure out what do people actually care
about? For example, if we take an
example of an app that helps you get to
sleep, right? If if you're helping me
get to sleep and you're asking me what
time I sleep and all of this stuff,
great, you're going to personalize it by
reminding me when I can go to sleep.
Great, this is cool.
But that's not really moving the needle
for me emotionally, right? It's not
doing much. It's it's very functional
and I understand, but it's not probably
the best example of personalization.
Whereas if we take an app that is to do
with improving your focus at work and
you're asking me what my job is and then
you're you're telling me that, you know,
CEOs, XYZ, developers, XYZ, you know,
train drivers, ABC. Now this is like,
ah, okay, this makes sense because it's
specifically for me in my context. So, I
think focusing personalization on
context as opposed to just focusing
personalization on questions, answers is
is a nice way to to wrap it up. Yeah,
that's some fantastic advice. I mean, so
many of these and and especially this
last kind of quick-fire round that we
did the last few minutes, it applies to
so many other aspects of your product as
well. It's like not just your onboarding
journey, but how do you personalize the
product? How do you find emotion and
like really show people that you're
delivering value in the product? How do
you incorporate social proof? Like I was
just using Strava last night and a
friend of mine from like 20 years ago
was on Strava and showed me that he's
like now an athlete competing in
triathlons and that was like a really
interesting social proof, you know,
moment for me of like, oh, that's really
cool. Like he's using Strava. I can
follow him on Strava. It's all of these
like apply throughout the entire product
journey. And so really fantastic advice.
As we wrap up, anything you want to
share and are you accepting clients at
at Perceptics currently? I know a lot of
growth
advisors are like booked up through
2025. Do you have any spots available? I
know after listening to this podcast,
some folks are going to want to get in
touch. We are pretty busy these days.
I'm pretty busy these days, but the team
is growing. So, we do we do have
capacity and we are taking on new
clients. And I'm also available to chat
all things web to app. Sometimes like
the best way is to just message me on
LinkedIn a question. Like because for
example, it may be the case that you
don't really need my services or our
services and you really just need a
little bit of advice and a kind of point
in the right direction. So more than
happy to do that as well. That's good
top of funnel marketing right there, you
know, give away a little bit, reel them
in. And definitely we're going to
include links but Nathan's been sharing
a ton on LinkedIn and then you you
started a YouTube channel as well,
right? So you're sharing a lot more like
video and and written content and slides
on LinkedIn and stuff. So great follow
on all those platforms. All right,
Nathan. Well, it's so much fun chatting
today and thanks for sharing all these
great nuggets and learnings that you had
over the years.
Thank you, Nathan. David, Jacob, thank
you. It's been a pleasure.
Thanks so much for listening.
If you have a minute, please leave a
review in your favorite podcast player.
You can also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.